# Sangwon Seo

(832) 839-3228 | ■ sangwon.seo@rice.edu | ★ sangwonseo.com
 in sangwon91 | ■ SangwonSeo\_ | ★ Google Scholar

### **About Me**

My research focuses on *Generative Models of Human Behavior*, *Human-Robot Collaboration*, and *AI-Assisted Decision Making*. During my PhD, I developed *imitation/reinforcement learning* algorithms capable of learning generalized agent policies from diverse human behaviors, as well as an *AI-driven team coaching system* that automatically analyzes and enhances teamwork in real time. I have published multiple first-author papers at top AI conferences.

I have strong programming skills, honed through hands-on experience at a medical AI startup before starting my PhD, where I developed commercial software for 3D medical image modeling. I highly value code maintainability and reproducibility. I firmly believe that these practices enable much faster development in the long run.

### **Education**

## **Rice University**, Houston, TX

Aug 2019 – Present

Ph.D. in Computer Science

• Thesis (Tentative): AI-Assisted Teamwork

### Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

*Mar 2013 – Feb 2015* 

M.S in Bioengineering

• Thesis: Performance Enhancement in Heart Rate Variability Analysis with Constrained Missing RR Interval Estimation

### Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2009 - Feb 2013

B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

• Thesis: Multiplexing of Bead-Based Immunoassays using a BioMEMS

## **Experience**

#### Honda Research Institute USA, San Jose, CA

May 2024 - Aug 2024

Research Intern

- Job Description: Human behavior modeling and optimization for human-aware automation
- Developed mathematical models to capture changes in human propensities for interacting with other agents and learned these models from demonstrations.
- Inferred individual interaction propensities with other agents from observable states and actions using sequential Monte Carlo methods

# **Human-Centered AI and Robotics Group**, Rice University, Houston, TX Ph.D. Candidate (Advisor: Prof. Vaibhay Unhelkar)

Aug 2020 - Present

- Thib. Candidate (Advisor, From Valbria)
- Proposed a team coaching AI algorithm to improve teamwork in real time during tasks
  Developed sample- and label-efficient imitation learning algorithms to learn a generative model of team behavior
- Developed a hierarchical imitation learning algorithm to learn the intentional behavior of experts from demonstrations
- Implemented multiple teamwork simulators and research tools
- Implemented a web-based interactive experiment framework and conducted human subject experiments

### Coreline Soft, Seoul, South Korea

Apr 2016 - Jun 2019

Associate Research Engineer

- Responsible for developing algorithms for AVIEW MODELER, a medical 3D printing solution
- Developed geometric modeling and processing algorithms
- Implemented a volume and surface rendering pipeline

### **Agency for Defense Development**, Daejeon, South Korea

Developed a telemetry system for aircraft

# **Biomedical Signal and Information Lab**, Seoul National University M.S Student (Advisor: Prof. Kwang Suk Park)

Feb 2013 - Feb 2015

- Developed signal/image processing algorithms for daily monitoring of physiological signals
- Developed autoregressive moving average-based interpolation methods to enhance heart rate variability analysis corrupted with missing measurements
- \* My employment at the Agency for Defense Development and Coreline Soft is recognized as fulfilling the military service in South Korea.

### **Publications**

- S. Seo and V. V. Unhelkar, "IDIL: Imitation Learning of Intent-Driven Expert Behavior", 23nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2024 (Acceptance rate 25%)
- S. Seo, "AI-Assisted Human Teamwork", AAAI-24 Doctoral Consortium, 2024
- **S. Seo**, B. Han and V. V. Unhelkar, "Automated Task-Time Interventions to Improve Teamwork using Imitation Learning", *22nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS)*, 2023 (Acceptance rate 23.3%)
- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "Semi-Supervised Imitation Learning of Team Policies from Suboptimal Demonstrations", *31st International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2022 (Acceptance rate 14.9%)
- **S. Seo**, L. R. Kennedy-Metz, M. A. Zenati, J. A. Shah, R. D. Dias and V. V. Unhelkar, "Towards an AI coach to infer team mental model alignment in healthcare", *2021 IEEE Conference on Cognitive and Computational Aspects of Situation Management (CogSIMA)*, pp. 39-44, 2021
- S. Kwon, D. Lee, J. Kim, Y. Lee, S. Kang, **S. Seo** and K. Park, "Sinabro: A smartphone-integrated opportunistic electrocardiogram monitoring system", *Sensors*, 16(3), p.361, 2016
- S. H. Hwang, S. Seo, H. N. Yoon, H. J. Baek, J. Cho, J. W. Choi, Y. J. Lee, D.-U. Jeong and K. Park, "Sleep period time estimation based on electrodermal activity", *IEEE journal of biomedical and health informatics (J-BHI)*, 21(1), pp.115-122, 2015
- S. Kang, S. Kwon, C. Yoo, **S. Seo**, K. Park, J. Song and Y. Lee, "Sinabro: Opportunistic and unobtrusive mobile electrocardiogram monitoring system", *15th Workshop on Mobile Computing Systems and Applications (HotMobile)*, pp. 1-6, 2014
- J. Kim, S. Kwon, S. Seo and K. Park, "Highly wearable galvanic skin response sensor using flexible and conductive polymer foam", 36th annual international conference of the IEEE engineering in medicine and biology society (EMBC), pp. 6631-6634, 2014

# **Working / Under-review Papers**

- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "Imitation Learning of Diverse Team Behavior from Heterogeneous Demonstrations", *Under Review*
- **S. Seo**, B. Han, R. E. Harari, R. D. Dias, M. A. Zenati, E. Salas and V. V. Unhelkar, "Socratic: Enhancing Human Teamwork via AI-enabled Coaching", *Under Review*
- Z. Qian, S. Seo, and V. V. Unhelkar, "Learning Human Preferences for Agent Behavior using Demonstrations and Large Language Models"

## **Honors & Awards**

National Scholarship for Science and Engineering, Korea Student Aid Foundation

Mar 2009

## **Teaching Experience**

## **Teaching Assistant**

COMP 646: Deep Learning for Vision and Language (Prof. Vicente Ordóñez-Román) Spring 2023 COMP 440/557: Artificial Intelligence (Prof. Devika Subramanian) Fall 2021

### **Advising & Mentoring**

Arnav Adhikari, Highschool Student, Houston, TX

Bing (Tim) Han, Undergraduate Student, Rice University

Zhanyi Sun, Undergraduate Student, Rice University

May 2023 – Dec 2023 May 2022 – May 2024 Jan 2022 – Jun 2022

### Reviewer \_\_\_\_\_

International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS) International Conference on Advanced Robotics and Its Social Impacts (ARSO) Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L) International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

### Skills

Programming Languages Python | C | C++ | Javascript | HTML | Matlab
FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES OpenGL | Flask | PyBullet | PyTorch | Tensorflow

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT Git | Docker | CMake | Shell Script | VSCode | Jupyter

ROBOT DEVELOPMENT Motion Capture (OptiTrack) | ROS | MoveIt | OMPL

LANGUAGES English | Korean

#### Extra

AAMAS Student Volunteer	2023
Student Venture Network, Seoul National University	Mar 2012 – July 2012
College of Engineering Tennis Club, Seoul National University	Mar 2010 – Feb 2013
System Administrator, ECE Department, Seoul National University	Mar 2010 – Feb 2011
SNU Mentoring, Seoul National University	Sep 2009 – Feb 2010